Amirali Omidfar

Software Engineer

Contact

Address

Fremont, CA, 94555

Phone

818.510.2546

E-mail

omidfar@ucla.edu

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/amirali-omidfar/

Skills

C/C++

Python

JAVA

JavaScript

HTML/CSS

SWIFT

Embedded Systems

Peripheral Communications: BLE,SPI,I2C,UART

Arduino, Raspberry Pi, STM32,ESP32,ESP8266, AVR, Dev Core boards I'm a 2nd year Electrical and Computer Engineering Masters' student at UCLA. As a graduate research assistant at UCLA HCI, I work on system design of projects that integrate deep learning and AI into user friendly human-computer interfaces. Other topics of my interest are Embedded Systems, AI on chip and Reinforcement learning in Robotics and path planning.

Work History

2020-06 -2020-12

Machine Learning and Embedded Systems Inten

TE Connectivity, Fremont, CA

- Received TE Spot Award for Self-driven project
 leadership and adaptability skills. Helped the team
 with reaching end of year's deadlines and
 milestones.
- Prototype a Haptic feedback controller (worked on both the firmware and the circuit design) for the medical unit project.
- Natural Language Processing for designing an Al-based search engine for TE's connectors
- Write firmware for STM32 MCU's using STMCube ID and mbed OS compiler

2019-05 -2021-01

Graduate Student Research Assistant

UCLA HCI, Los Angeles, CA

- Research on interactive and ubiquitous technologies for IoT devices.
- Designing a universal wrist-worn controller utilizing deep learning on IMU and image data
- Visual Assistive technologies and indoor navigation systems for visually impaired people.
- Publication pending at Augment Humans 2021

2015-01 -2015-08

Control Engineering Co Op

Whirlpool, Amana, IA

- LED light bulb cost optimization project (1.5 million\$
 Annual Saving) Statistical Analysis of luminosity and color temperature (CCT) of LED light bulbs
- Whirlpool Co Op Award for LED project, embracing teamwork and excellent communication skills.

PCB Design

Neural Networks and Deep Learning

Reinforcement Learning

Natural Language Processing

- Test engineer ice maker UI interface
- Design an inspection device for measuring luminosity and CCT of the lighting inside refrigerators.

Education

2019-08 -	Master of Science: Electrical and Computer
2021-02	Engineering
	University Of California - Los Angeles - Los Angeles, CA
2016-08 -	Bachelor of Science: Electrical Engineering
2019-03	University Of California - Los Angeles - Los Angeles, CA